{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","address":"2001 W Warren Ave","zipcode":"48208","owner":"Detroit Board of Education","licenseNumber":"034989","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"5/15/2017","establishmentType":"Public School","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":null,"reviewFrequencyDays":"210.0","geom":"0101000020E6100000980BC9BA59C554C0184010A4BB2C4540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"42463","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","inspectionDate":"2018-06-08T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"95","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"4","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"4","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42463","inspectionDate":"6/8/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"ice bin(s) in ice machine","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"Through out the day as necessary","location":"PREP AREA(S)","subLocation":"At the Ice machine","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-08T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"inspectionid":"42463","inspectionDate":"6/8/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"Equipment can openers","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"PREP AREA(S)","subLocation":"At the Can opener","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-08T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"42463","inspectionDate":"6/8/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"5-402.11","violationDescription":"Except as otherwise allowed, a direct connection may not exist between the SEWAGE system and a drain originating from EQUIPMENT in which FOOD, portable EQUIPMENT, or UTENSILS are placed. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Backflow/backsiphonage prevention device(s)","subItem":"Air gap","problemDescription":"Not provided on","subProblem":"Ice machine","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Ice machine","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-08T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide adequate air gap."},{"inspectionid":"42463","inspectionDate":"6/8/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"6-202.15","violationDescription":"Outer openings of a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT shall be protected against the entry of insects and rodents. Unless otherwise allowed by law. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Outer opening(s)","subItem":"door(s)","problemDescription":"Not sealed to prevent pest entry","subProblem":"","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"At the Back door","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair"},{"inspectionid":"42463","inspectionDate":"6/8/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"6-501.112","violationDescription":"Dead or trapped birds, insects, rodents, and other pests shall be removed from control devices and the PREMISES at a frequency that prevents their accumulation,  decomposition, or the attraction of pests.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Dead/trapped pest(s)","subItem":"rodents mice","problemDescription":"Not removed from facility","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE AREA(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-08T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Remove from facility/premises."},{"inspectionid":"42463","inspectionDate":"6/8/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"6-501.111","violationDescription":"The presence of insects, rodents, and other pests shall be controlled to minimize their presence on the PREMISES.  by:\r\n(A) Routinely inspecting incoming shipments of FOOD and supplies; \r\n(B) Routinely inspecting the PREMISES for evidence of pests;\r\n(C) Using methods, if pests are found, such as trapping devices or other means of pest control as specified.(Pf) \r\n(D) Eliminating harborage conditions. \r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Pest(s)","subItem":"rodents mice","problemDescription":"Present in facility","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE AREA(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-06-08T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Remove pests from facility."}]},{"inspectionid":"40394","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","inspectionDate":"2017-09-27T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"131","pcount":"1","pfcount":"0","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"1","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"1","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"40394","inspectionDate":"9/27/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"At the COLD HOLDING TEMPERATURES","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-27T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"}]},{"inspectionid":"39085","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","inspectionDate":"2017-06-23T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"83","pcount":"0","pfcount":"2","ccount":"1","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"1","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"39085","inspectionDate":"6/23/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Single-service/single-use article(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-06-23T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."},{"inspectionid":"39085","inspectionDate":"6/23/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\r\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-06-23T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"inspectionid":"39085","inspectionDate":"6/23/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-06-23T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide adequate sanitary hand drying aids/devices."}]},{"inspectionid":"37501","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","inspectionDate":"2016-12-07T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"127","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"37501","inspectionDate":"12/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"disposable, paper towels","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-12-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide"},{"inspectionid":"37501","inspectionDate":"12/7/2016","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"952","name":"Douglass Academy For Young Men","violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Quaternary ammonia solution","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 100 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-12-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"952"}}